

# **Collins Kiprop Kiptanui**

**Date of birth:** 10/05/1996 | **Nationality:** Kenyan | **Phone number:** (+254) 706767859 (Mobile) | **Phone number:** 

(+49) 17660801083 (Work) | Email address: collinskiprop6@gmail.com | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/collins-kiprop-419b55190

Address: Vogelsang 121, 38118, Braunschweig, Germany (Home)

#### About me:

I am a Data Scientist with a strong mathematical background and experience in using predictive modelling, data processing, machine learning, cloud computing, SQL and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. I am involved in python open source community and passionate about utilizing the resources in data science to solve problems in different fields.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

24/10/2022 - 31/12/2022 Helmstedt, Germany

#### FULFILLMENT ASSOCIATE AMAZON FULFILLMENT WAREHOUSE

- 1. Receive and put away inventor.
- 2. Get customer orders ready and pack them up.
- 3. Load boxes into trucks for shipment.
- 4. Use scanners to read bar codes on products.
- 5. View prompts on screens and follow the direction for some tasks.
- 6. Troubleshoot problems.
- 7. Ensure product meets quality requirements.

02/04/2020 - 31/12/2021 Nairobi, Kenya

# **DATA ANALYST / ACCOUNTANT** TRANS TECH INTERNATIONAL COMPANY LIMITED APRIL 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

- Preparation of monthly management accounts.
- Timely and up to date bank reconciliations.
- Preparation of audit schedules both for internal and external audit.
- Prepare monthly financial statements, reports and records by collecting, analyzing and summarizing account information.
- Identify and define the objectives of an assigned marketing research project; determines the best methods to use to meet those objectives.
- Draft guestionnaires, polls, surveys, and other data collection resources.
- Research and compile data related to current product market, customer demographics and interest, and factors influencing product demand; analyze results to identify ways of maximizing sales and market penetration of current products.
- Compile data related to competitors products such as pricing, sales, and marketing or distribution methodology.
- Summarize and analyze data; make recommendations related to research findings.

03/05/2018 - 26/02/2020 Nairobi, Kenya

#### STATISTICS AND DATA ANALYSIS INTERN KENYA MEDICAL RESEARCH INSTITUTE

#### Studies:

- 1. Assessing health factors and Experiences associated with Khat handling, and chewing in selected areas in Kenya.
- 2. A Baseline Survey for Nestle Health kids program roll out in schools in Meru, Murang'a, and Nyeri counties.
- 3. NHIF Survey; A study to determine whether the KEMRI employees are studied with their NHIF cover.

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Executing data quality protocols and internal quality checks to ensure complete and accurate databases are maintained.
- 2. Data collection, data cleaning, data analysis and presentation to a panel of scientists.
- 3. Designing XLS format for the data collection tools for Open Data Kit (ODK) to enhance electronic data collection.

30/04/2018 - 29/09/2018 Eldoret, Kenya

#### **ACTUARIAL INTERN** MOI TEACHING AND REFERRAL HOSPITAL

- 1. Collection of primary and secondary data.
- 2. Hospital data analysis using MS Excel.
- 3. Special clinics management.
- 4. Health Management Information Systems (Data entry and analysis using DHIS-2).
- 5. Measles campaign (Data entry).

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

28/04/2022 - CURRENT Braunschweig, Germany

MASTER'S DEGREE IN DATA SCIENCE Technical University of Braunschweig

Address Universitätspl. 2, 38106 Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

Website <a href="https://www.tu-braunschweig.de/">https://www.tu-braunschweig.de/</a>

10/09/2014 - 28/11/2019 Nairobi, Kenya

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ACTUARIAL SCIENCE** Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Address P.O. Box 62000 – 00200 NAIROBI, KENYA, Nairobi, Kenya | Website http://www.jkuat.ac.ke/

13/03/2010 - 04/11/2014 Kapsabet, Kenya

KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION Kapsabet Boys High School

Address P.O Box 10, C 36, Kapsabet, Kapsabet, Kenya | Website http://kapsabet.boys.high.school.co.ke/

08/01/2005 - 15/10/2009

KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION Roseve Educational Center

Address P.O. Box 657, Kapsabet | Website http://roseve.ac.ke/

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **SWAHILI** | **ENGLISH** | **KALENJIN** 

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
GERMAN	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### DIGITAL SKILLS

Data Gathering, Data Processing, Data Visualization, Data Analysis | Programming languages (Python and R program) | SQL (MySQL) | Cloud computing | Software Architecture | Machine learning | Git

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

# **RECOMMENDATIONS**

Anthony Mwangi Colleague

Director at Trans-tech international Company Limited

**Email** <u>fiabletraders@gmail.com</u> | **Phone** (+254) 716344564

Maxmiller Keitany Colleague

Prosecutor at Office of Director of Public Prosecution

**Email** kmaxmiller@gmail.com | **Phone** (+254) 724701697

Nelson Ouma Statistician- Kenya Medical Research Institute

My supervisor at the Kenya Medical Research Institute.

**Email** <u>nellomondis@gmail.com</u> | **Phone** (+254) 704722919